NYSUT Photographs 6174 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
NYSUT Photographs
1988-1996
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State United Teachers (NYSUT)
6174 P
1.83 cubic feet
1.8 linear ft.
Photographs.
6849962
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 16, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 24, 2016
Biographical / Historical
New York State United Teachers (NYSUT) was created in 1972 by the merger of the New York State Teachers Association (NYSTA) and the United Teachers of New York (UTNY). NYSTA had been affiliated with the National Education Association (NEA), and UTNY with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT). UTNY was the statewide organization whose United Federation of Teachers (UFT), led by Albert Shanker, was the predominant teachers' union in New York City. In joining with United Teachers and affiliating with the AFT, NYSUT also became a member union of the AFL-CIO.
In 1976, NYSUT voted to disaffiliate with the NEA. Some locals left NYSUT and created the NYEA (New York Educators Association), which became the state affiliate for the NEA. In the early 1980s, NYEA changed its name to NEA-NY.
NYEA/NEA- NY viewed association with the AFL-CIO's industrial unions as undermining the professional image and independence of teachers. The two organizations also differed strongly on aspects of the governance structure, particularly with respect to ethnic minority representation, with NYSUT opposed to mandatory minimums. The rivalry between NYSUT and NYEA/NEA-NY in organizing new locals expended a great deal of resources for both labor organizations.
While competition with NYEA/NEA-NY was a constant focus of NYSUT's organizing efforts for teachers, NYSUT was also organizing college faculty members, nurses, and other non-teaching personnel. Once members were organized, NYSUT continued to advocate for teachers' and other workers' rights through contract support and legal services at the local level and political involvement at the state and federal levels, supporting candidates and legislation that protected funding, due process, and working conditions.
NEA-N Y merged with NYSUT in 2006, by which time NYSUT had grown to more than half a million members, becoming the largest union in New York State.
Scope and Contents
Mostly photos of NYSUT president Tom Hobart, some other labor and political leaders, 1969-2001
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6174/017 MB: NYSUT General Officers Memorabilia 6174: NYSUT Records 6174 AV: NYSUT Audio-Visual Materials 6174 MB: NYSUT Memorabilia 6174 OH: NYSUT Oral History Interviews 6174 PUBS: NYSUT Publications 6174/001: NYSUT President's Office Files 6174/001 P: NYSUT President's Office Photographs 6174/002: NYSUT Vice President's Office files 6174/003: NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services. Files 6174/004: NYSUT Field Services Department Files 6174/004 AV: NYSUT Field Services Department Audio-Visual Material 6174/005: NYSUT Legislative Department Files 6174/006: NYSUT Public Relations Department Files 6174/007: NYSUT New York Special Task Force on Equity and Excellence in Education Files 6174/008: NYSUT Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Files 6174/009: NYSUT Teacher Education Conference Board Files 6174/010: NYSUT Convention files 6174/011: NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office Files 6174/012: NYSUT "Teachers United: The Rise of NYSUT" Research Notes 6174/013 AV: NYSUT Representative Assembly (RA) Audio-Visual materials 6174/014: NYSUT Alan Lubin Files 6174/015: NYSUT Boards of Directors Meetings 6174/016: NYSUT Vice-President's Office Maria Neira. Files 6174/017: NYSUT General Officers Records 6174/017 AV: NYSUT General Officers Audio-Visual Materials 6174/017 P: NYSUT General Officers Photographs 6174/018: NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, Maria Neira Files 6174/019: NYSUT Biography File
Teachers' unions -- New York (State); New York State United Teachers; New York State United Teachers --Photographs
6849962
- A conference on Public School financing (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  18 slides
- NYSUT - Research and Education Dept. -- Central NY Educational Conference - 4/6/1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  30 photographs
- NYSUT Research and Education Dept. -- Central NY Educational Conference -- 3/15/1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  25 photographs
- Photographs from York State Manor taken in late Spring of 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  6 photographs and negative sheets
- Asian Clothing Workers at work in a factory (Box 1, Folder 5)
  42 color photographs and negatives
- Jim Conti photographs (Box 1, Folder 6)
  'Jim Conti' is noted on the back of several of the photographs, no other info given - 11 photographs
- NEA - Conference photographs (Box 1, Folder 7)
  10 color, 16 black and white photographs, negatives
- Set of transparencies made up for 1969 State Aid Campaign (Box 1, Folder 8)
  17 transparencies
- Nelson Rockefeller-Educational Conference Board, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Gov. Rockefeller with NYS Educational Conference Board
- Solidarnosc 1989-1990 (1) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Photos of NYSUT president Tom Hobart with Solidarnosc leader Lech Walesa, New York governor Mario Cuomo, Wiktor Kulerski (Teachers Solidarity), and others; newspaper clippings; list of Polish trip participants -- 26 photographs
- Solidarnosc 1989-1990 (2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Photos of NYSUT president Tom Hobart with Solidarnosc leader Lech Walesa, New York governor Mario Cuomo, Wiktor Kulerski (Teachers Solidarity), and others; newspaper clippings; list of Polish trip participants -- 25 photographs
- Executive Committee - 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Photos of Hobart, Al Shanker, Antonia Cortese, and others -- 4 photographs
- Executive Committee - 1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Photo of Hobart, Cortese, and others at 1996 Representative Assembly -- 1 photograph
- Hobart Formal Portraits - c. 1980-2001 (1) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Formal portraits -- 26 photographs
- Hobart Formal Portraits - c. 1980-2001 (2) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Hobart Formal Portraits - c. 1980-2001 (3) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Formal portraits -- 20 photographs
- Hobart Group - 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Photos of Hobart with Gov. Mario Cuomo, Antonia Cortese -- 22 photographs
- Hobart Group - 1971-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Photos of Hobart and other labor and political leaders -- 26 photographs
- Hobart Group - 1971-1991 (2) (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Hobart Group - 1971-1991 (3) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Hobart Group - 1971-1991 (4) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Photos of Hobart and other labor and political leaders -- 2 photographs; 19 photo copies; 1 slide
- Hobart Group, Cleary - c. 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Photos of Hobart with Gov. Mario Cuomo, NYS AFL-CIO president Ed Cleary, others -- 4 photographs
- Hobart Group, Regents c. 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Photos of Hobart with Gov. Mario Cuomo, others -- 4 photographs
- Hobart Group, Texaco - c. 1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Photos of Hobart with Gov. Mario Cuomo, others -- 8 photographs
- Hobart Personal - c. 1975-1986 (1) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Photos of Hobart with family members and others, on international trips, to New York City, Hawaii, and elsewhere -- 25 photographs
- Hobart Personal - c. 1975-1986 (2) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Photos of Hobart with family members and others, on international trips, to New York City, Hawaii, and elsewhere -- 32 photographs
- Hobart, Negatives and Proofs (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Negatives and proof sheets of Hobart with others
- Hobart Group Activities -- 1981-1992 (1) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Photos of Hobart with delegation including Secretary General of the National Teachers Council of Thailand, 1984; photos with NYS AFL-CIO president Ed Cleary, Gov. Mario Cuomo, and others, engaged in speaking and other activities -- 26 photographs
- Hobart Group Activities -- 1981-1992 (2) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Photos of Hobart with delegation including Secretary General of the National Teachers Council of Thailand, 1984; photos with NYS AFL-CIO president Ed Cleary, Gov. Mario Cuomo, and others, engaged in speaking and other activities -- 14 photographs
- Autographed - n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Photographs of Hobart pictured with and signed by various leaders, including Roots author Alex Haley, vice president Walter Mondale, president Jimmy Carter, president Ronald Reagan, chief justice Warren Burger, senator Daniel Patrick Moynihan, governor Mario Cuomo, attorney general Robert Abrams -- 9 photographs
- Gov. Mario Cuomo (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Photos of Gov. Mario Cuomo, with Hobart or others -- 23 photographs
- Special - c. 1972-1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Photo of Hobart with labor leader Jack Sheinkman, with cover letter from Sheinkman, February 26, 1987; photo of Hobart with Sen. Jacob Javits; others -- 8 photographs; news clippings
- Miscellaneous - c. 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Photos of Hobart at the Northeast Hispanic Scholarship Foundation event, October 1988; photos of Hobart at Representative Assembly journalism awards and New York Consumer Assembly events; river view of NYC skyline, with Twin Towers in background; photos of Labor Day parade with NYSUT float, in Williamsville, NY, 1988; other group photos -- 24 photographs
- AFL-CIO 100th Anniversary Convention - Labor's Centennial -- 1881-1981 -- New York City, New York -- Nov. 16, 1981 (Box 4 (1OP))
  - AFL-CIO Hundredth Anniversary Convention, 1981 (Box 41OP, Folder 1)
    Panoramic view of convention